<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-06-01T10:46:37-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Blogs Archive</title><subtitle>This is an archive of the Roller blogs that were previously hosted on blogs.apache.org</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Meet Rohit Yadav - the new VP of Apache CloudStack</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/meet-rohit-yadav-the-new" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Rohit Yadav - the new VP of Apache CloudStack" /><published>2023-05-03T14:13:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-05-03T14:13:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/meet-rohit-yadav-the-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/meet-rohit-yadav-the-new">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/f702f145-bcc3-4a5b-8c61-26aa671bf977&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/f702f145-bcc3-4a5b-8c61-26aa671bf977&quot; alt=&quot;ACS-Kubecon.jpg&quot; width= &quot;750&quot; height = &quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CloudStack Community is happy to announce Rohit Yadav as the new VP of the Apache CloudStack Project and PMC chair. After a year of success in which Simon Weller chaired the project, we are now excited to welcome Rohit, who is a long-term contributor to the project. He has a strong technology background and has been engaged in the open-source world for more than a decade, during which he contributed to multiple other open-source projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this interview, you will be able to learn more about Rohit Yadav and see his perspective on the VP&apos;s role and how he can contribute to the Apache CloudStack project evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do you&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;believe in open-source, where and how did it all start?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: left;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/e0fac3b3-be00-4d5e-9e8c-0d64d61deb5f&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;163&quot; height=&quot;163&quot; hspace=&quot;20&quot; vspace=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my university days, I got introduced to open-source as a way of community-driven development. Compared to proprietary and closed-source software, I found the idea of open-source remarkable that anybody can access source code, learn it, modify it, distribute it, and even contribute it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my spare time, I started learning and contributing to a few open-source projects as a hobby and even created some open-source side-projects. I also got an opportunity to work with the VideoLAN project as a Google Summer of Code and later worked as a volunteer summer student at CERN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this early experience inculcated an interest in open-source and virtualisation, and eventually, I was hired straight out of university by Citrix to work on open-source Apache CloudStack project that was still in the ASF incubator at the time. This is when I learned about the ASF and how to work in the Apache CloudStack community from my colleagues and from the community, and I learnt how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://infra.apache.org/contributors.html&quot;&gt;contribute changes&lt;/a&gt;. I started lurking and interacting on the project &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudstack.apache.org/mailing-lists.html&quot;&gt;mailing lists&lt;/a&gt; and IRC to understand how to work in this community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quickly found myself supporting users on the mailing lists and learning real-world use of CloudStack, contributing patches such as maintaining our (new) maven-based build system, working on some issues and making some improvements. I also &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cloudstack-cloudmonkey&quot;&gt;wrote the cloudmonkey CLI&lt;/a&gt; because there wasn&amp;rsquo;t one available and I also ended-up working on a large APIs refactoring project that helped me understand CloudStack deeper and work closely with the original creators and architects of CloudStack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this, I was invited to become a committer to the project and got sponsored to participate in the first CloudStack Collaboration Conference 2012 in Las Vegas. After another few years of working on flagship CloudStack features, frameworks, releases, maintaining CloudStack and collaborating with the community, I eventually got invited to become a PMC member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve transitioned into a more supporting, mentoring, empowering and leadership role in the community and at work. This allows me to find time and bandwidth to champion and promote Apache CloudStack in all forums and platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/9e380bde-e7d7-4a2c-8a16-cd0afc413051&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should enterprises use open&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-source&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;solutions? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprises nowadays are adopting open-source software especially when it comes to infrastructure software. This gives them business advantage in keeping low costs and not having to depend on a single vendor (no vendor lock-in) while have the longevity, trust, stability, reliability, durability, flexibility, better agility and security, and access to an ecosystem of community and commercial offerings and support around it. There is also community and inter-organisation collaborations on standards, frameworks and feature development that help reduce costs for the end-consumers, including the enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprises also attract better talent as it&amp;rsquo;s generally much easy to hire or train talent on open-source software with its documentation and other types of training materials in the form of books, blogs and videos etc., accessible to everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine any enterprise and any consumer product or service that won&amp;rsquo;t have any open-source project used in their stacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are the existing enterprise users of Apache CloudStack and how are they benefiting?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anybody looking to implement (private or public) IaaS cloud should seriously consider CloudStack. It is easy to-use, cost-effective, very stable, massively scalable, highly reliable battle-tested IaaS cloud computing platform, well-known and used in production at many of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest organisations. The project is community-driven by diverse contributors who are deeply invested in solving real-world &lt;a href=&quot;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/CLOUDSTACK/Case+Studies&quot;&gt;use-cases&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to take my word for it - as an open-source top-level &lt;a href=&quot;https://apache.org/&quot;&gt;ASF&lt;/a&gt; project anybody can test drive and see it for themselves, there is no vendor lock-in or paywall to get started. It takes a very short amount of time and effort to set it up, perhaps a few hours or less for a seasoned administrator. We have &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.cloudstack.apache.org/en/latest/quickinstallationguide/qig.html&quot;&gt;quick install guides&lt;/a&gt; for anybody to get started and even a public simulator-based demo environment for anybody with a few minutes to try it out, get the look-and-feel for it at &lt;a href=&quot;https://qa.cloudstack.cloud/simulator/&quot;&gt;https://qa.cloudstack.cloud/simulator/&lt;/a&gt; using the demo-environment credentials admin:password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CloudStack is very easy to deploy, use and manage. Being a monolith application, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to upgrade, can be managed by a small team. It is feature-rich, and offers a great UI, APIs and rich tooling and libraries such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cloudstack-cloudmonkey&quot;&gt;cloudmonkey&lt;/a&gt; (cmk, the official CLI), the CloudStack &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cloudstack-terraform-provider&quot;&gt;Terraform provider&lt;/a&gt;, the CloudStack &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cloudstack-kubernetes-provider&quot;&gt;Kubernetes provider&lt;/a&gt;, the CloudStack &lt;a href=&quot;https://cluster-api-cloudstack.sigs.k8s.io/&quot;&gt;Cluster-API Provider (CAPC)&lt;/a&gt;, the CloudStack &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cloudstack-go&quot;&gt;Go-SDK&lt;/a&gt;, support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.ansible.com/ansible/latest/scenario_guides/guide_cloudstack.html&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;, and countless other integration, libraries and related projects in its ever-growing ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an open-source project, Apache CloudStack project does not track who uses it. Still, we have a fair idea of our user base based on the community-maintained and contributed &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudstack.apache.org/users.html&quot;&gt;list of users&lt;/a&gt; on our project website. Also, based on activities and representation by such users and their organisations in the community by their participation on the mailing lists, around releases, issue reporting and code contributions on Github, attendance and participation in project meetups and conferences, and other forums such as blogs, videos, websites, press releases, social media etc. These enterprises, organisations and users include some of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest Fortune 500 companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get super motivated and content when I read CloudStack &lt;a href=&quot;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/CLOUDSTACK/Case+Studies&quot;&gt;case-studies&lt;/a&gt; or when I learn where and how our work on CloudStack benefits the core mission of companies. In the most recent CloudStack Collab conference, I was delighted to learn how CloudStack &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xq2LVY18GU8&quot;&gt;empowers the Digital India&lt;/a&gt; mission that helped &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cowin.gov.in/&quot;&gt;vaccinate billions&lt;/a&gt; as well as delivers digital product and services to citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is Apache CloudStack project evolving and where do you see its future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen a steady stream of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cloudstack/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;developer contribution&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cloudstack/releases&quot;&gt;releases&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re seeing CloudStack getting more and more polished with every release. We&amp;rsquo;ve grown into a pedigree of PMC members, committers, contributors and power users who have been around in the community for a long time, a decade or more now. This demonstrates the reliability, durability and stability the project offers to the users community and the trust of the users community who are continuing to use and support CloudStack over the years. We&amp;rsquo;re seeing CloudStack adoption growing steadily from users participation on mailing lists, Github, meetups and conferences and release adoption. Per the hype curve, we&amp;rsquo;re in the plateau of productivity so this isn&amp;rsquo;t surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have always been a community-driven project and that should continue. We may also see interesting integrations, features and other changes to align with the changing themes and trends of the industry and the users community, we may find such use-cases in AI, data sovereignty, privacy and cloud-repatriation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to ensure there&amp;rsquo;s a healthy community that feels welcome to use CloudStack, report issues, participate on the mailing lists and in meetups and conferences, and tell us about their use-cases and problems in all such forums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The users community should be supported to contribute to CloudStack, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shapeblue/hackerbook&quot;&gt;train&lt;/a&gt; on CloudStack, help contribute fixes, enhancements and feature that solves their problems, and invite them to become committers and PMC members of the project. As long we support a healthy feedback loop and maintain the cycle of the project it will continue to grow, evolve, and thrive. We also need more efforts towards project marketing and promotion, and some work on strategic features, frameworks and integrations that leads to more growth and adoption of CloudStack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start contributing!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to become a committer and join a great community? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudstack.apache.org/contribute.html&quot;&gt;Read on!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Ivet Petrova&quot;, &quot;login&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet@apache.org&quot;}</name><email>ivet@apache.org</email></author><category term="Meet the Community" /><summary type="html">The CloudStack Community is happy to announce Rohit Yadav as the new VP of the Apache CloudStack Project and PMC chair. After a year of success in which Simon Weller chaired the project, we are now excited to welcome Rohit, who is a long-term contributor to the project. He has a strong technology background and has been engaged in the open-source world for more than a decade, during which he contributed to multiple other open-source projects.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">1 Week to Go - CloudStack European User Group - May 4th, 2023</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/cloudstack-european-user-group-may1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="1 Week to Go - CloudStack European User Group - May 4th, 2023" /><published>2023-04-27T10:29:32-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-27T10:29:32-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/cloudstack-european-user-group-may1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/cloudstack-european-user-group-may1">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/59255fe4-a752-4813-bb46-61a1089ace99&quot; alt=&quot;https___cdn.evbuc.com_images_428670709_1347400005383_1_original.jpeg width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;European CloudStack Community&lt;/strong&gt; is counting down the days until CloudStack European User Group 2023. The event will be taking place in &lt;strong&gt;London&lt;/strong&gt;, in the Gandhi Room at Cifas, Tavistock Square, 7-12 Lynton House, London, WC1H 9LT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join technical talks, user stories, new features, integrations presentations and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Become part of the CSEUG on May 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2023!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/cloudstack-european-user-group-2023-tickets-513821653397&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REGISTER FOR FREE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12:00 - 12:15&lt;/strong&gt; - Welcome, Giles Sirett, Chairman, CloudStack European User Group&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12:15 - 12:45&lt;/strong&gt; - What&amp;rsquo;s new at CloudStack 4.18, Giles Sirett&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12:55 - 13:25&lt;/strong&gt; - CloudStack Monitoring, Lucian Burlacu, ShapeBlue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13:35 - 14:05&lt;/strong&gt; - News about LINBIT SDS &amp;amp; CloudStack, Philipp Reisner, LINBIT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14:05 - 14:30&lt;/strong&gt; - Coffee Break&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14:30 - 15:00&lt;/strong&gt; - Re-using old hardware, thus saving money and the environment, Wido den Hollander, Your.Online&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15:10- 15:40&lt;/strong&gt; - Network Service Chaining in Core and Edge Zones, Alexandre Mattioli, ShapeBlue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15:50 - 16:20&lt;/strong&gt; - A proposal - make changes in Apache CloudStack faster and low risk with vendor CI systems, Alex Ivanov, Niki Tenev, StorPool&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16:30 - 17:00&lt;/strong&gt; - Dimsi and Backroll : What&amp;rsquo;s new/next release, Pierre Charton, Pierre de La Ville and Ousmane Diarra, Dimsi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meet the Speakers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Giles Sirett&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giles is a committer, PMC member of the Apache CloudStack project and Chairman of the European CloudStack User Group. He is also CEO &amp;amp; founder of ShapeBlue, the leading independent CloudStack integrator &amp;amp; consultancy. He has worked with many high-profile organisations, helping them strategise, design and implement CloudStack based clouds. Giles is an active contributor to the Apache CloudStack project and has spoken at all CloudStack Collaboration conferences, Linuxcon, and other events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lucian Burlacu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucian is a long-time sysadmin and Apache Cloustack user and contributor. He has a background in hosting, virtualisation and datacentre operations, but is now working full time on CloudStack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phillip Reisner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philipp Reisner is founder and CEO of LINBIT in Vienna/Austria. His professional career has been dominated by developing DRBD, a storage replication for Linux. Today he leads a company of about 30 employees with locations in Vienna, Austria and Portland, Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wido den Hollander&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wido den Hollander is the CTO at Your.online. Wido has been a part of the CloudStack community since 2012. Ever since he has contributed various parts of code like Ceph/RBD, IPv6, KVM and many other parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexandre Mattioli&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexandre Mattioli is a highly experienced Infrastructure Architect who has been working with Apache Cloudstack since 2015, he has designed, built and operated one of the largest ACS clouds in existence and led a team to design and productise many diverse solutions on top of ACS. He&apos;s currently a Cloud Architect at ShapeBlue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alex Ivanov&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Ivanov is the Product Lead at StorPool Storage and is responsible for the product strategy and tactics at the company. He has experience in the storage market and a deep understanding of the needs and priorities of businesses managing large-scale clouds to run diverse, mission-critical workloads. At StorPool, he works closely with the team to evolve the StorPool primary storage platform and expand its capabilities and usefulness for various use cases. His goal - ensure StorPool cost-effectively delivers above and beyond what is possible with other primary storage products to help customers achieve their commercial and technical goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niki Tenev&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niki is a Solutions Architect at StorPool Storage. He worked as a System Administrator for a decade, and later on, his interest and career gradually shifted to business and product development. Together with the StorPool team, Niki helps companies build resilient and agile clouds that fit the needs of their specific projects. In his spare time, Niki practices the technique of folding clothes while people are still in them (a.k.a. Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pierre Charton&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pierre is in charge of Backroll integration inside CloudStack for DIMSI. Pierre has a proven track record of successful c# and Java projects. When not playing with his keyboard, Pierre is surfing, WingFoiling or bodyboarding on the Brittany coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The event will happen on May 4th, starting at 12pm GMT and finishing at 5pm GMT.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/59255fe4-a752-4813-bb46-61a1089ace99&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Ivet Petrova&quot;, &quot;login&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet@apache.org&quot;}</name><email>ivet@apache.org</email></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">The European CloudStack Community is counting down the days until CloudStack European User Group 2023. The event will be taking place in London, in the Gandhi Room at Cifas, Tavistock Square, 7-12 Lynton House, London, WC1H 9LT. Join technical talks, user stories, new features, integrations presentations and more! Become part of the CSEUG on May 4th, 2023! REGISTER FOR FREE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflecting on KubeCon + CloudNativeCon 2023</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/reflecting-on-kubecon-cloudnativecon-2023" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflecting on KubeCon + CloudNativeCon 2023" /><published>2023-04-27T09:09:47-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-27T09:09:47-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/reflecting-on-kubecon-cloudnativecon-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/reflecting-on-kubecon-cloudnativecon-2023">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/e729f7ae-ebe1-474a-91f6-27c6a581b995&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/e729f7ae-ebe1-474a-91f6-27c6a581b995&quot; alt=&quot;ACS-Kubecon.jpg&quot; width= &quot;750&quot; height = &quot;520&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first year, the Apache CloudStack Community has participated at KubeCon + CloudNativeCon- the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cncf.io/?_gl=1*x7ihno*_ga*MjA1MDg5MzgzMS4xNjc5OTAwNzUy*_ga_VWZ4V8CGRF*MTY4MjQwNDA5NC4xMS4wLjE2ODI0MDQwOTQuMC4wLjA.&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-preserver-spaces=&quot;true&quot;&gt;Cloud Native Computing Foundation&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-preserver-spaces=&quot;true&quot;&gt; flagship conference, which gathers adopters and technologists from leading open source and cloud native communities. It has been a fantastic opportunity for us to represent our technology on the global stage, and meet engineers, DevOps and infrastructure experts. Community members have had the pleasure of running attendees through multiple CloudStack demos and answering their many questions about the open-source cloud management solution. We also had the opportunity to share the pitfalls, hacks, learnings, and key takeaways from&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AR8JXotMir8&amp;amp;t=44s&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-preserver-spaces=&quot;true&quot;&gt;our journey to develop CAPC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-preserver-spaces=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; the CAPI Provider for Apache CloudStack.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The CloudStack Booth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community members representing and sharing knowledge of Apache CloudStack with the broader cloud industry had a thoroughly enjoyable time at the conference. We manage to engage with global cloud providers, telecoms, consulting companies, gaming companies and service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed a lot with attendees on topics like building hybrid clouds, keeping infrastructure costs under control, decreasing cloud complexity, and ensuring the best infrastructure for running containers at scale while maintaining investments in infrastructure low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/40babcd3-3ee6-4b8f-8b05-a1ac8507c6ff&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/bf09db74-8261-4f1d-9001-d1d7b4f1cf23&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/7346597f-2b13-44c7-aa67-95eb337145c9&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explore the Kubernetes Cluster API Provider for Apache CloudStack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kubernetes Cluster API (CAPI) provider for Apache CloudStack allows Kubernetes users to build and manage resources on Apache CloudStack. The provider is available under the Apache 2 open-source license and is managed by the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF). The Cluster API brings declarative, Kubernetes-style APIs to cluster creation, configuration and management. The API itself is shared across multiple cloud providers allowing for true Apache CloudStack hybrid deployments of Kubernetes. It is built atop the lessons learned from previous cluster managers such as kops and kubicorn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discover the Upcoming CloudStack Events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CloudStack European User Group:&lt;/strong&gt; The next event that the Apache CloudStack community is hosting is the CloudStack European User Group&lt;strong&gt;, taking place on 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May&lt;/strong&gt; in the Gandhi Room at Cifas, Tavistock Square, 7-12 Lynton House, &lt;strong&gt;London&lt;/strong&gt;, WC1H 9LT. This event is an annual 1-day technical event for the European CloudStack community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/cloudstack-european-user-group-2023-tickets-513821653397&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Click here to register for CSEUG)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CloudStack Collaboration Conference: &lt;/strong&gt;Taking place on &lt;strong&gt;23-24&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; November&lt;/strong&gt;, with the location to be announced in the new future, CCC is the most significant global CloudStack and open-source cloud builders event. The two-day hybrid event is aimed at developers, operators and users to discuss and evolve the open-source software project, its functionality and real-world operability. This event will introduce you to the CloudStack family, community leaders, project members and contributors. Registration details will be announced &lt;strong&gt;in the near future,&lt;/strong&gt; so make sure to keep an eye out on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudstack.apache.org/mailing-lists.html&quot;&gt;CloudStack mailing lists&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CloudStack&quot;&gt;CloudStack&amp;rsquo;s social media&lt;/a&gt; channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudstackcollab.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Sponsorship-Prospectus-CCC-2023.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Learn about sponsorship opportunities)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Choose Apache CloudStack &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache CloudStack helps cloud builders solve their key challenges &amp;ndash; costs, vendor lock-in and using fewer resources to manage tens of thousands of physical servers installed in geographically distributed data centers. The turnkey solution, made for cloud builders and managed service providers, is open-source and easy to implement, manage and scale - particularly when compared to alternative cloud orchestration platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the latest 4.18 release - https://bit.ly/3Koczl3&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Ivet Petrova&quot;, &quot;login&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet@apache.org&quot;}</name><email>ivet@apache.org</email></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">For the first year, the Apache CloudStack Community has participated at KubeCon + CloudNativeCon- the&amp;nbsp;Cloud Native Computing Foundation&amp;rsquo;s flagship conference, which gathers adopters and technologists from leading open source and cloud native communities. It has been a fantastic opportunity for us to represent our technology on the global stage, and meet engineers, DevOps and infrastructure experts. Community members have had the pleasure of running attendees through multiple CloudStack demos and answering their many questions about the open-source cloud management solution. We also had the opportunity to share the pitfalls, hacks, learnings, and key takeaways from&amp;nbsp;our journey to develop CAPC&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; the CAPI Provider for Apache CloudStack.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meet Apache CloudStack at KubeCon + CloudNativeCon 2023</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/meet-apache-cloudstack-at-kubecon" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Apache CloudStack at KubeCon + CloudNativeCon 2023" /><published>2023-04-17T10:27:28-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T10:27:28-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/meet-apache-cloudstack-at-kubecon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/meet-apache-cloudstack-at-kubecon">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/fe5aa3f1-cd92-4cfa-a092-a595d3b9ffd4&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/fe5aa3f1-cd92-4cfa-a092-a595d3b9ffd4&quot; alt=&quot;ACS-Kubecon.jpg&quot; width= &quot;750&quot; height = &quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On 18-21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; April, in Amsterdam, Netherlands will take place one of the largest flagship cloud conferences globally &amp;ndash; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KubeCon + Cloud NativeCon.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to share that Apache CloudStack will be a silver sponsor at the event, and that community members will be representing the technology and community on the global stage. Attendees will be able to come to the Apache CloudStack booth and learn more about the capabilities and use cases of CloudStack as a turnkey solution for cloud management. This will help further propel the awareness of Apache CloudStack, across an audience of leading cloud providers, MSPs and telcos. Meet us at booth S52!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe/register/&quot; style=&quot;background-color: #70A7C5; color: white; padding: 1em 1.5em; text-decoration: none; text-transform: uppercase;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;REGISTER NOW&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apache CloudStack&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;at &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe/&quot;&gt;KubeCon + CloudNative Con&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being part of KubeCon + CloudNativeCon is yet another level of progression for our community, as our representatives will be meeting a number of organisations in the Kubernetes ecosystem, introducing them to the technology for the first time, as well as showing recent and upcoming features to existing users. In particular, we will share the pitfalls, hacks, learnings, and key takeaways from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AR8JXotMir8&amp;amp;t=44s&quot;&gt;our journey to develop CAPC&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; the CAPI Provider for Apache CloudStack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a 20% discount for &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KubeCon + CloudNative Con 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; with&amp;nbsp;Apache CloudStack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a silver sponsor of KubeCon + CloudNative Con, we have the chance to give away 20% discount codes to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are two types of passes the 20% discount code can be used for:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In-Person KubeCon + CloudNativeCon Only Corporate Attendee Pass:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Includes access to keynotes, sessions, exhibit hall, and all other programs that do not require a separate registration and/or fee on the main conference days, April 19-21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Includes full attendee access to the virtual event platform&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In-Person All-Access Corporate Attendee Pass:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Includes all features of the KubeCon + CloudNativeCon Only Corporate Attendee Pass&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Includes access to all CNCF-hosted co-located events on April 18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to redeem the code, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudstack.apache.org/mailing-lists.html#:~:text=To%20Subscribe%20to%20the%20Mailing,%40cloudstack.apache.org.&quot;&gt;get in touch with us on the CloudStack&amp;rsquo;s mailing lists.&lt;/a&gt; and ask for the code to be applied during registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudstack.apache.org/mailing-lists.html#:~:text=To%20Subscribe%20to%20the%20Mailing,%40cloudstack.apache.org.&quot; style=&quot;background-color: #70A7C5; color: white; padding: 1em 1.5em; text-decoration: none; text-transform: uppercase;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;SUBSCRIBE&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Ivet Petrova&quot;, &quot;login&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet@apache.org&quot;}</name><email>ivet@apache.org</email></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">On 18-21st April, in Amsterdam, Netherlands will take place one of the largest flagship cloud conferences globally &amp;ndash; KubeCon + Cloud NativeCon. We are excited to share that Apache CloudStack will be a silver sponsor at the event, and that community members will be representing the technology and community on the global stage. Attendees will be able to come to the Apache CloudStack booth and learn more about the capabilities and use cases of CloudStack as a turnkey solution for cloud management. This will help further propel the awareness of Apache CloudStack, across an audience of leading cloud providers, MSPs and telcos.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apache Causeway version 2.0.0-RC1 Released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/isis/entry/apache-causeway-version-2-0" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apache Causeway version 2.0.0-RC1 Released" /><published>2023-03-26T14:36:22-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-26T14:36:22-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/isis/entry/apache-causeway-version-2-0</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/isis/entry/apache-causeway-version-2-0">&lt;p&gt;T&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;he Apache Causeway team is pleased to announce the release of Apache Causeway 2.0.0-RC1.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;The main highlight is the change of name (to the new name &apos;causeway&apos;, from the old name &apos;isis&apos;), which means that all Maven artifacts as well as package names have changed.&amp;nbsp; The migration notes [1] explain how to update your code; if you need assistance then reach out through the mailing list [2] or our slack channel [3] because we can explain how to tackle change in stages.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div&gt;In addition, there are a small number of new features in this release, as well as numerous improvements and bug fixes.&amp;nbsp; The new features include:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;* a new PageRenderSubscriber SPI provides callbacks to track the time taken to render a page (CAUSEWAY-3373)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;* a new service to generate HTML documentation based on the domain model (CAUSEWAY-3328)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;* the simplification of the view model lifecycle by allowing injected dependencies to be specified as constructor parameters (CAUSEWAY-3293)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;* a new BackgroundService that allows actions to be executed via a Quartz job (CAUSEWAY-3267)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;* allowing SAFE semantics actions to be invoked with only VIEWING permission (CAUSEWAY-3358)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;Full release notes are available on the Apache Causeway website at [4].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You can access this release directly from the Maven central repo [5].&lt;br&gt;Alternatively, download the release and build it from source [6].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Enjoy!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;--The Apache Causeway team&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1]&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://causeway.apache.org/relnotes/2.0.0-RC1/2023/2.0.0-RC1/mignotes.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://causeway.apache.org/relnotes/2.0.0-RC1/2023/2.0.0-RC1/mignotes.html&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1679927583803000&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw0XvSu8Ylp7dz7AeonzPYpX&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(17, 85, 204);&quot;&gt;https://causeway.apache.&lt;wbr&gt;org/relnotes/2.0.0-RC1/2023/2.&lt;wbr&gt;0.0-RC1/mignotes.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;[2]&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://causeway.apache.org/docs/2.0.0-RC1/support/mailing-list.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://causeway.apache.org/docs/2.0.0-RC1/support/mailing-list.html&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1679927583803000&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3CLPDncqOJHph2XHvKGeVJ&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(17, 85, 204);&quot;&gt;https://causeway.apache.&lt;wbr&gt;org/docs/2.0.0-RC1/support/&lt;wbr&gt;mailing-list.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;[3]&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://causeway.apache.org/docs/2.0.0-RC1/support/slack-channel.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://causeway.apache.org/docs/2.0.0-RC1/support/slack-channel.html&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1679927583803000&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw05lwDvbMN1KDIX9uwfRV5z&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(17, 85, 204);&quot;&gt;https://causeway.apache.&lt;wbr&gt;org/docs/2.0.0-RC1/support/&lt;wbr&gt;slack-channel.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;[4]&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://causeway.apache.org/relnotes/2.0.0-RC1/about.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://causeway.apache.org/relnotes/2.0.0-RC1/about.html&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1679927583803000&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw196GLkfcTgyhkc106OJ3VS&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(17, 85, 204);&quot;&gt;https://causeway.apache.org/&lt;wbr&gt;relnotes/2.0.0-RC1/about.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;[5]&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://search.maven.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://search.maven.org&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1679927583803000&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw385d99A1SYKByJh5CuRGSO&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(17, 85, 204);&quot;&gt;https://search.maven.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;[6]&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://causeway.apache.org/docs/2.0.0-RC1/downloads/how-to.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://causeway.apache.org/docs/2.0.0-RC1/downloads/how-to.html&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1679927583803000&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3rDX4HZ74yaWWvh2pmWmI4&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(17, 85, 204);&quot;&gt;https://causeway.apache.org/&lt;wbr&gt;docs/2.0.0-RC1/downloads/how-&lt;wbr&gt;to.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Dan Haywood&quot;, &quot;login&quot;=&gt;&quot;danhaywood&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;danhaywood@apache.org&quot;}</name><email>danhaywood@apache.org</email></author><category term="Announcements" /><category term="causeway" /><category term="rest" /><category term="framework" /><category term="rad" /><category term="java" /><category term="ddd" /><category term="rename" /><summary type="html">The Apache Causeway team is pleased to announce the release of Apache Causeway 2.0.0-RC1. The main highlight is the change of name (to the new name &apos;causeway&apos;, from the old name &apos;isis&apos;), which means that all Maven artifacts as well as package names have changed.&amp;nbsp; The migration notes [1] explain how to update your code; if you need assistance then reach out through the mailing list [2] or our slack channel [3] because we can explain how to tackle change in stages. In addition, there are a small number of new features in this release, as well as numerous improvements and bug fixes.&amp;nbsp; The new features include:* a new PageRenderSubscriber SPI provides callbacks to track the time taken to render a page (CAUSEWAY-3373) * a new service to generate HTML documentation based on the domain model (CAUSEWAY-3328) * the simplification of the view model lifecycle by allowing injected dependencies to be specified as constructor parameters (CAUSEWAY-3293) * a new BackgroundService that allows actions to be executed via a Quartz job (CAUSEWAY-3267) * allowing SAFE semantics actions to be invoked with only VIEWING permission (CAUSEWAY-3358) Full release notes are available on the Apache Causeway website at [4].You can access this release directly from the Maven central repo [5].Alternatively, download the release and build it from source [6].Enjoy!--The Apache Causeway team[1]&amp;nbsp;https://causeway.apache.org/relnotes/2.0.0-RC1/2023/2.0.0-RC1/mignotes.html [2]&amp;nbsp;https://causeway.apache.org/docs/2.0.0-RC1/support/mailing-list.html [3]&amp;nbsp;https://causeway.apache.org/docs/2.0.0-RC1/support/slack-channel.html [4]&amp;nbsp;https://causeway.apache.org/relnotes/2.0.0-RC1/about.html[5]&amp;nbsp;https://search.maven.org[6]&amp;nbsp;https://causeway.apache.org/docs/2.0.0-RC1/downloads/how-to.html</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 3 at CloudFest</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/day-3-at-cloudfest" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 3 at CloudFest" /><published>2023-03-23T10:48:16-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-23T10:48:16-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/day-3-at-cloudfest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/day-3-at-cloudfest">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/c199e71b-acd8-4caa-a08a-a36522ffa125&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/c199e71b-acd8-4caa-a08a-a36522ffa125&quot; alt=&quot;cloudstack booth.jpg align =&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;567&quot; height=&quot;425&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is day 3 at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudfest.com/&quot;&gt;CloudFest&lt;/a&gt;. Apache CloudStack exhibiting at the conference has been nothing short of fantastic. Community members representing the technology have had the chance to meet many like-minded people and showcase the power of the leading open-source IaaS management solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Choose Apache CloudStack If You Are A Cloud Builder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A problem that many businesses face when entering the public cloud market is finding the suitable software and partners which enable a rapid deployment for their customers. Often, it takes up a significant number of resources and can have a negative financial impact on the company if the wrong decision is made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CloudStack is a turnkey solution for cloud builders and manages service providers. It is completely open-source, easy to implement, manage and scale. Powered by a large open-source community and following rapid release cycles, Apache CloudStack help cloud builders solve their key challenges &amp;ndash; costs, vendor lock-in and using fewer resources to manage tens of thousands of physical servers installed in geographically distributed data centers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Attend CloudFest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you are still open to attending the last day of CloudFest tomorrow, or attending the event next year, we recommend all cloud specialists to join the event.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CloudFest in the #1 internet infrastructure event in the world, connecting the global cloud computing industry. It is the largest and most important cloud event of the year. The event gathers over 7000 attendees, making it the perfect place for networking, collaboration and attending some exciting sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/0b9ef48b-dc67-4f40-bfab-7db3d2162c59&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/0b9ef48b-dc67-4f40-bfab-7db3d2162c59&quot; alt=&quot;cloudfest.jpg width=&quot;750&quot; height =&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s Sessions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some highlights of today&amp;rsquo;s sessions can be seen below. To see the event schedule in its entirety, &lt;strong&gt;visit the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudfest.com/agenda&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;official event website.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/11ea3fea-4b0d-473b-8d0d-32641542c6be&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/11ea3fea-4b0d-473b-8d0d-32641542c6be&quot; alt=&quot;session 1.png width=&quot;694&quot; height=&quot;124&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/fbc9fa75-fd48-413d-8866-3622f8eb53e3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/fbc9fa75-fd48-413d-8866-3622f8eb53e3&quot; alt=&quot;session 2.png width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;125&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/2d95e42d-2b12-4c1e-b1ea-2ce0c91216d7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/2d95e42d-2b12-4c1e-b1ea-2ce0c91216d7&quot; alt=&quot;session 3.png width=&quot;697&quot; height=&quot;128&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Ivet Petrova&quot;, &quot;login&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet@apache.org&quot;}</name><email>ivet@apache.org</email></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">It is day 3 at CloudFest. Apache CloudStack exhibiting at the conference has been nothing short of fantastic. Community members representing the technology have had the chance to meet many like-minded people and showcase the power of the leading open-source IaaS management solutions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 2 at CloudFest</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/day-2-at-cloudfest" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 2 at CloudFest" /><published>2023-03-21T15:49:44-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-21T15:49:44-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/day-2-at-cloudfest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/day-2-at-cloudfest">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/487d1056-5072-4756-bd2e-3d863a8000d0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/487d1056-5072-4756-bd2e-3d863a8000d0&quot; alt=&quot;cloudfest 1.jpg width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today marks the second day of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudfest.com/&quot;&gt;CloudFest&lt;/a&gt;, the #1 internet infrastructure event in the world. As you may know, Apache CloudStack is an exhibitor at the conference, with a number of community members representing the technology and community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Come and Meet Apache CloudStack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For attendees who are currently at the conference, we invite you to come and speak to us. Apache CloudStack&amp;rsquo;s booth is G19. Come and introduce yourself and discover the benefits of using an open-source technology for building a private cloud or delivering public cloud services. We are also keen to discuss Apache CloudStack with new potential users and technologies which would like to integrate with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/b60375b1-33e8-4a40-bf89-4f5ba5527b0e&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/b60375b1-33e8-4a40-bf89-4f5ba5527b0e&quot; alt=&quot;cloudfest 3.jpg width=&quot;378&quot; height=&quot;504&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What You Can Learn About CloudStack at CloudFest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At CloudStack&amp;rsquo;s booth you can meet part of the most active contributors to the open-source project. This gives you a chance to discover the newest features and capabilities of CloudStack. Our community members will be happy also to organize a personalized CloudStack demo for you and to discuss what technologies can help you improve your cloud&amp;rsquo;s profitability and decrease the complexity of managing large-scale IaaS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, at the CloudStack booth you can find people from leading cloud providers, who will share their experience with the technology and will give valuable advice on building cloud infrastructure with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploring CloudStack 4.18 Release&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All people who met us today found out exclusive details on the upcoming 4.18 release. Our community members took the chance to showcase which are the new features within CloudStack and what advantages it gives to cloud providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sessions Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CloudFest Day 2 started with an agenda full of interesting talks from leading cloud providers and companies developing solutions for the industry. Part of the talks, which we found interesting are Distributed Cloud Computing: A New Approach by Akamai, The Resilient Hard Disk Drive (1984 to 2062) by Toshiba, Scalable Edge Data Centers: Current Challenges and How to Overcome Them by german Edge Cloud, a panel discussion on Building Sustainable Data Centers and Making Multicloud Happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you will be visiting CloudFest, be sure you stop at the CloudStack booth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/603f0617-7dce-4a70-a2e0-f9785f247a6a&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/603f0617-7dce-4a70-a2e0-f9785f247a6a&quot; alt=&quot;cloudfest 2.jpg width=&quot;378&quot; height=&quot;504&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Ivet Petrova&quot;, &quot;login&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet@apache.org&quot;}</name><email>ivet@apache.org</email></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">Today marks the second day of CloudFest, the #1 internet infrastructure event in the world. As you may know, Apache CloudStack is an exhibitor at the conference, with a number of community members representing the technology and community.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CloudStack Helps proIO to Become a More Profitable and Successful Managed Service Provider</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/becoming-a-profitable" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CloudStack Helps proIO to Become a More Profitable and Successful Managed Service Provider" /><published>2023-03-21T15:44:23-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-21T15:44:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/becoming-a-profitable</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/becoming-a-profitable">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/af41609f-8555-4238-8989-6159bc577516&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/af41609f-8555-4238-8989-6159bc577516&quot; alt=&quot;YO-cs-1200-628.jpg&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Delivering cloud solutions need not be as complex and costly as some would have thought. With the right technology stack, companies can quickly and easily deploy a flexible and stable IaaS offering to support any business requirements, as proIO discovered.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.proio.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;proIO&lt;/a&gt; was founded in Frankfurt, Germany, nearly 20 years ago, as Swen Br&amp;uuml;seke explains. &amp;ldquo;We wanted to create a company based on holistic IT concepts, providing support and advice from system design and creation through to smooth day-to-day running of operations.&amp;rdquo;, said &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Swen Br&amp;uuml;seke, CEO of proIO.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The company started by remotely looking after its customer&amp;rsquo;s physical servers and data centres in both Frankfurt and Hamburg - 24/7. This has grown to the extent that they now support thousands of physical servers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;During the last few years, customer demand has led proIO to extend its support services with a fully managed cloud offering to become a Managed Service Provider specialising in open-source Linux applications.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/3e00b9f9-a6a1-482f-972f-1b8f2819d4d9&quot; style=&quot;background-color: #70A7C5; color: white; padding: 1em 1.5em; text-decoration: none; text-transform: uppercase;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;DOWNLOAD THE CASE STUDY&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Move to CloudStack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The company migrated its cloud to CloudStack in 2019 for a number of reasons, as Swen explained. &amp;ldquo;We had used it for several years on various other projects, and so we had acquired a great amount of working knowledge. This experience demonstrated to us how easy it was to set up a proof of concept and deploy a CloudStack-based solution. It was also much easier to keep up to date once deployed compared to other solutions we had looked at.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fully Redundant Infrastructure Based on Open-Source Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Currently, more than 95% of proIO&amp;rsquo;s virtual machines are Linux based. &amp;ldquo;Our customers are not bothered whether their operating system is open source or not,&amp;rdquo; explained Swen. &amp;ldquo;They just want their apps to run to support their business. We now look after all types of customers from healthcare, hotel booking, through automotive and clothing to publishing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/3e00b9f9-a6a1-482f-972f-1b8f2819d4d9&quot; style=&quot;background-color: #70A7C5; color: white; padding: 1em 1.5em; text-decoration: none; text-transform: uppercase;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;DOWNLOAD THE CASE STUDY&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s great the way that everybody helps each other out in the community, contributing what they can to ensure CloudStack continues to develop and refine as a product. I would recommend CloudStack wholeheartedly to any organisation that is looking at developing a cloud-based infrastructure.&amp;rdquo;, says &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Swen Br&amp;uuml;seke, CEO of proIO.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Ivet Petrova&quot;, &quot;login&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet@apache.org&quot;}</name><email>ivet@apache.org</email></author><category term="Case Studies &amp; Integrations" /><summary type="html">Delivering cloud solutions need not be as complex and costly as some would have thought. With the right technology stack, companies can quickly and easily deploy a flexible and stable IaaS offering to support any business requirements, as proIO discovered.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apache CloudStack 4.18.0.0 LTS Release</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/apache-cloudstack-4-18-0" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apache CloudStack 4.18.0.0 LTS Release" /><published>2023-03-20T11:23:28-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-20T11:23:28-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/apache-cloudstack-4-18-0</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/apache-cloudstack-4-18-0">&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/6f7aa770-3f15-45d0-b27a-c3666a659caf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/6f7aa770-3f15-45d0-b27a-c3666a659caf&quot; alt=&quot;CloudStack_New-Release-4-18_1200x628px.jpg width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apache Software Foundation Announces Apache&amp;reg; CloudStack&amp;reg; v4.18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache CloudStack 4.18.0.0 is a 4.18 LTS release with 300+ new features, improvements, and bug fixes since 4.17, including 19 major new features. Some of the highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Edge Zones&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Autoscaling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Managed User Data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Two-Factor Authentication Framework&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Support for Time-based OTP (TOTP) Authenticator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Volume Encryption&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;ins cite=&quot;mailto:Marco%20Sinhoreli&quot; datetime=&quot;2023-01-23T14:03&quot;&gt;SDN Integration &amp;ndash; Tungsten Fabric&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Ceph Multi Monitor Support&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; API-Driven Console Access&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Console Access Security Improvements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; New Global settings UI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Configurable MTU for VR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Adaptative Affinity Groups&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Custom DNS Servers for Networks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Improved Guest OS Support Framework&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Support for Enterprise Linux 9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Networker Backup Plugin for KVM Hypervisor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Custom Quota Tariffs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Secure VNC for KVM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full list of new features can be found in the project release notes at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.cloudstack.apache.org/en/4.18.0.0/releasenotes/changes.html&quot;&gt;http://docs.cloudstack.apache.org/en/4.18.0.0/releasenotes/changes.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CloudStack documentation includes upgrade instructions from previous versions of Apache CloudStack, and can be found at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.cloudstack.apache.org/en/4.18.0.0/upgrading/index.html&quot;&gt;http://docs.cloudstack.apache.org/en/4.18.0.0/upgrading/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The official installation, administration and API documentation for each of the releases are available on our documentation page:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.cloudstack.apache.org/&quot;&gt;http://docs.cloudstack.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Downloads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The official source code for the 4.18.0.0 release can be downloaded from our downloads page: &lt;a href=&quot;http://cloudstack.apache.org/downloads.html&quot;&gt;http://cloudstack.apache.org/downloads.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the official source code release, individual contributors have also made convenience binaries available on the Apache CloudStack download page, and can be found at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://download.cloudstack.org/ubuntu/dists/&quot;&gt;https://download.cloudstack.org/ubuntu/dists/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://download.cloudstack.org/centos/7/&quot;&gt;https://download.cloudstack.org/centos/7/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://download.cloudstack.org/centos/8/&quot;&gt;https://download.cloudstack.org/centos/8/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://download.cloudstack.org/suse/15&quot;&gt;https://download.cloudstack.org/suse/15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shapeblue.com/packages/&quot;&gt;https://www.shapeblue.com/packages/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Ivet Petrova&quot;, &quot;login&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet@apache.org&quot;}</name><email>ivet@apache.org</email></author><category term="Announcements" /><summary type="html">&amp;nbsp; The Apache Software Foundation Announces Apache&amp;reg; CloudStack&amp;reg; v4.18. Apache CloudStack 4.18.0.0 is a 4.18 LTS release with 300+ new features, improvements, and bug fixes since 4.17, including 19 major new features.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Future-Proof Open-Source Platform Hosting Millions of Websites for Your.Online</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/future-proof-open-source-platform" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Future-Proof Open-Source Platform Hosting Millions of Websites for Your.Online" /><published>2023-03-08T10:11:11-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-08T10:11:11-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/future-proof-open-source-platform</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cloudstack/entry/future-proof-open-source-platform">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/4d7d7c8f-3951-4d15-9340-b1360357d6f7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/4d7d7c8f-3951-4d15-9340-b1360357d6f7&quot; alt=&quot;YO-cs-1200-628.jpg&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://your.online/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Your.Online&lt;/a&gt; is a team of pioneers from all over the world united by the passion for helping businesses succeed online. Their teams of local experts provide highly standardized managed services to high-intent customers to reach their full online potential. The group serves over 1 million customers and generates &amp;euro;175m in revenue with its eight brands and 600 employees.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your.Online needed to build a centralized IaaS cloud platform for four of their brands - Versio, Yourhosting, Savvii and Axarnet. The four companies ran on different infrastructure platforms using technologies like VMware, RHEV, Xen server, Virtuozzo, Proxmox, custom-built solutions and many others. This made it extremely hard and nearly impossible to manage their infrastructure centrally and ensure reliability and operational effectiveness.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/d9f0bb38-580a-411c-9318-b1a11143e881&quot; style=&quot;background-color: #70A7C5; color: white; padding: 1em 1.5em; text-decoration: none; text-transform: uppercase;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;DOWNLOAD THE CASE STUDY&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building a Centralised Platform Based on CloudStack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your.Online has built a centralized platform powered by CloudStack, Ceph, TrueNAS and KVM to be utilized by all their hosting brands. The new solution allowed the company to simplify infrastructure management and have end-to-end visibility of the processes inside from a single pane of glass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your.Online uses BGP, EVPN and VXLAN with CloudStack&amp;rsquo;s Advanced networking model. This allows them to scale networks very easily in a redundant and high-performant way over multiple data centers. This is a built-in functionality of CloudStack, which when combined with IPv6 support and security groups makes for a modern and future-proof solution, on which they can continue to invest and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/85db8d29-cf32-409b-b3b2-1d23df9f598d&quot; alt=&quot;Wido.png width=&quot;128&quot; height=&quot;135&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; hspace=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ensuring Reliability in the Long Term&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;ldquo;One of the reasons to centralize on CloudStack is to have one single point of truth about the utilization of our assets. One overview of the VMs, assets and capacity utilization. Now we can automate against one platform, and for us, the main driver to choosing CloudStack was that it is an open-source project governed by the Apache Software Foundation. We know it is a stable platform both from a technical and legal perspective. The project will be live in the next ten years, allowing us to avoid the risk associated with commercial projects - usually licensing and governance problems.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Wido den Hollander, CTO, Your.Online&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.apache.org/cloudstack/mediaresource/d9f0bb38-580a-411c-9318-b1a11143e881&quot; style=&quot;background-color: #70A7C5; color: white; padding: 1em 1.5em; text-decoration: none; text-transform: uppercase;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;DOWNLOAD THE CASE STUDY&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Your.Online&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://your.online/&quot;&gt;Your.Online&lt;/a&gt; is a leading European online services platform supporting businesses of all sizes in realizing and scaling their online ambitions. The company is a team of pioneers from all over the world united by the passion of helping businesses succeed online. Their team consists of local experts providing highly standardized managed services to high-intent customers to reach their full online potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In building a future of more online possibilities, they focus on using climate-friendly data centers, use highly efficient hardware, continuous focus on further optimization of their infrastructure, prolonging the use of servers as much as possible and professionally recycling the ones that are no longer functional. All these priorities create both business value and sustainable impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Apache CloudStack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache CloudStack is an open-source cloud management solution designed to deploy and manage large networks of virtual machines, as a highly available, highly scalable Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) cloud computing platform. CloudStack is used by a number of service providers to offer public cloud services, and by many companies to provide an on-premises (private) cloud offering, or as part of a hybrid cloud solution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;display_name&quot;=&gt;&quot;Ivet Petrova&quot;, &quot;login&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet&quot;, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;ivet@apache.org&quot;}</name><email>ivet@apache.org</email></author><category term="Case Studies &amp; Integrations" /><summary type="html">Your.Online is a team of pioneers from all over the world united by the passion for helping businesses succeed online. Their teams of local experts provide highly standardized managed services to high-intent customers to reach their full online potential. The group serves over 1 million customers and generates &amp;euro;175m in revenue with its eight brands and 600 employees.&amp;nbsp; Your.Online needed to build a centralized IaaS cloud platform for four of their brands - Versio, Yourhosting, Savvii and Axarnet. The four companies ran on different infrastructure platforms using technologies like VMware, RHEV, Xen server, Virtuozzo, Proxmox, custom-built solutions and many others. This made it extremely hard and nearly impossible to manage their infrastructure centrally and ensure reliability and operational effectiveness.&amp;nbsp;</summary></entry></feed>